[Music]
increased risk of Parkinson's disease
has been associated with exposure to
pesticides consumption of dairy products
a history of melanoma and traumatic
brain injury why is the risk of
Parkinson's disease increased among
individuals with high milk and dairy
consumption uh it could be the animal
fat maybe the animal protein so why not
use a plant food diet for the risk and
management of Parkinson's disease there
are phytochemicals that may Target the
underlying cause but in terms of
treatment ancient sacred texts from
thousands of years ago refer to
Trembling individuals who are prescribed
a plant from the bean family to treat
the condition in my last video I talked
about the use of velvet beans but in
1913 the miracle drug lopa was
discovered for the first first time in
fabba beans also known as fava beans or
broad beans as a natural source of L
Doopa to consider the amount varies
considerably based on number of factors
but typically it looks like they have
about 10 times less than velvet beans
but that's okay since you can eat larger
quantity since fava beans are an actual
food instead of a powdered supplement
the important thing is that the amount
of elop in fava beans is enough to be
pharmacologically active in Parkinson's
disease in fact there's some reports
indicating that Parkinson's patients
might respond better to the beans than
to standard elopa preparations in pill
form but anecdotal reports that patients
May gain benefit from a broadbean rich
diet don't cut it what you have to do is
put it to the test Parkinson's patients
were fed about one and A3 cups of cooked
fava beans and during the next 4 hours a
substantial clinical Improvement was
noted in fact similar to the Improvement
seen after receiving the standard
pharmacological combination of lopa plus
Carbidopa the decarboxylase inhibitor
drug I talked about in the last video
that boosts lopa levels in the brain no
surprise that there was a similar effect
since they had very similar lopa levels
in the blood in fact half the time you
could hardly tell the beans from the
drugs how could there be the same levels
if the bean elopa lacked the Carbidopa
booster drug because fava beans may not
only be a natural source of elopa but a
natural source of the Carbidopa boost
too so the consumption of fava beans has
the potential to increase the levels of
vopa and Carbidopa in the blood with a
market Improvement and muscle movement
performance of the patients with
Parkinson's disease without any side
effects in fact they work so well you
have to be careful about abruptly
stopping them there's a condition called
neuroleptic malignant like syndrome
characterized by fever rigidity all
sorts of neurological problems muscle
breakdown altered levels of
consciousness which is usually
precipitated by an AB rupt withdrawal of
the lopa drug caused by an acute
dopamine deficient State well you can
see the same thing if you're treating
your Parkinson's with fava beans and
then all of a sudden stop them 10 days
before hospital admission this poor
guy's Garden ran out of beans leading to
a severe crippling rigidity this case
demonstrates that alternative therapies
carry similar risks to traditional
agents because in this case they really
are the ultimate traditional agent there
are some downsides you don't see with
the drug though like fava induced
flatulence you also have to be careful
with fava consumption if you're on MAO
inhibitor drugs often used as
anti-depressants since there could be
drug
interactions and then there's the risk
of a condition known as favism there's a
genetic mutation that occurs in about
120 people and at even higher rates in
those of African Asian and Mediterranean
descent in which people lack an enzyme
that's necessary to detoxify certain
compounds found in fava beans and
without the enzyme fava Bean consumption
can cause your red blood cells to
rupture thankfully genetic testing for
this mutation is widely available and
affordable so it seemed prudent to
screen patients with Parkinson's for
this favism what's called G6PD
deficiency mutation prior to putting
them on daily fava Bean consumption if
you want to give fava beans a try fresh
green fava beans have significantly more
elopa than dried so much so that dried
FAA beans may not provide any clinical
benefits roasting and boiling removes
some or even all the Elba though other
Studies have found about a half cup of
cooked favas contain approximately 250
milligrams sprouted favas may have the
most increasing up until day nine by
which time the indigestible flatulent
sugars may be eliminated offering
another advantage of fava Bean sprouting
but you don't know if fava bean sprouts
help until you put them to the test
researchers fed Parkinson's patients a
salad with about a half cup of freshly
chopped fava sprouts and observed
substantial clinical
Improvement other beans just like
regular beans also naturally have lopa
though at lower amounts soybeans have a
bonus compound that may act as an lopa
boosting Carbidopa compound what if you
fed people's soybeans on top of their
regular Parkinson's meds giving people
just one and a half spoonfuls worth of
roasted soybeans led to a significant
improvement over the drugs alone with
significantly fewer involuntary
movements hours later until more
information is available Parkinson's
combo drugs like cinnam should remain
the first line therapy but adding beans
to one's diet may only
[Music]
help for